=== PAGE 70 ===
This P.C.C. assumes that the psychic was a young, nonnal 
man or woman who has suddenly discovered new abilitie s, and 
may soon be forced to abandon his/her nonnal life. 
The Powers of a Psychic: 
1. At first level, the psychic automatically has the following 
abilities: 
See Aura 
Sense Evil 
Meditation 
Presence Sense 
2. Addit ional psionic abiliti es: In addition to the above, the 
psychic character gets to select two powers from each of the 
healing, sensitive and physical categories. One additional power 
can be selected from any category for each additional level of 
experience. 
3. I.S.P. : To detennine the character 's amount of Inner 
Strength Points, take the number of M.E. as the base, roll 
ID 4x1O , and add it to the base number. The character gets an¡
other 10 LS .P. for each additional level of experience. Consid¡
ered to be a master psionic . 
4. P.P.E .: Most of the character' s P.P.E. has been expended in 
the development of psychic abilit ies. Pennanent P.P.E. Ba se : 
ID 6. 
Attribute Requi rements : Only psionic powers, but a high LQ. 
and M.E. are strongly recommended. 
P.C.C. Skills : Detennine the character's work or educational 
background. A college student might have a good grasp of 
two or three scientific or technical skills, while a blue-collar 
worker might know a number of mechanical, electronic or 
domestic skills. 
Spe ak/Literate in Native Language 98% 
Select 4 work -related/educational -related skills (+ 15% ) 
Select I Domestic skill of choice (+ I 0% ) 
Hand to hand: basic can be selected as one "other" skill, 
hand to hand: expert at the cost of two "other" skills, or mar¡
tial arts (or assassin if an evil alignment) for the cost of three 
"other" skills. 
P.C .C. Related Skills: Sel ect 10 other skills. Plus one additional 
skill at levels three, five, eight, ten and thirteen. All new skills 
start at the base skill level. 
Communications : Any 
Domestic : Any (+5%) 
Electrical : Any (+5%) 
Espionage : Wild erness surviva l only. 
Mecha nical : Any (+5%) 
Medical: Any (any skill other than first aid, holistic medicine 
and Paramedic counts as two skill selecti ons, howeve r) 
Military : None 
Physical : Any 
Pilot: Any (+5%) 
Pilot Related: Any 
Rogue : Any 
Science : Any (+5%) 
Techn ical : Any (+5%) 
W.P.: Any 
Wild erness: Any (+5%) 
Secondary Skills : The character also gets to select six secon¡
dary skills. These are additional areas of knowled ge that do 
69 
not get the benefit of the bonuses listed in parentheses. All 
secondary skills start at the base skill level . 
Standard Equipment: Varies with occupation/background, plus 
a basic car, pick-up truck or motorcycle. 
Money : 3D6x 10 0 in cash and ID 6x l ,000 in possessions. 
Descriptions of Psychic Abili ties 
AN ALPHABETICAL LIST OF 
ALL PSYCHIC ABILITIES 
Sensitive 
Astral Projection 
Clairvoyance 
Death Trance 
Divina tion 
Physical 
Empathic Transmission 
Empathy 
Alter Aura 
Bio-Manipulation 
Death Trance 
Ectoplasm 
Electrokine sis 
Hydrokinesis 
Impervious to Cold 
Impervious to Fire 
Impervious to Poison 
Levitation 
Meditation 
Mediumship/Clairsentience 
Mind Block 
Object Read/Psychometry 
Presence Sense Meditation 
See Aura 
See the Inv isible 
Sense Evil 
Sense Magic 
Si xth Sense 
Speed Reading 
Su ggest ion 
Mind Block 
Pyrokinesis 
Resist Fatigue 
Resist Hunger 
Resist Thirst 
Su mmon Inner Strength 
Telepathy 
Speed Reading 
Su mmon Inner Strength 
Telekinesis 
Total Recall 
Total Recall 
Healer 
Deaden Pain 
Exorcism 
Healing 
Healing Touch 
Impervious to Cold 
Impervious to Fire 
Increase Healing 
Induce Pain 
Induce Sl eep 
Psychic Diagnosis 
Psychic Purification 
Psychic Surgery 
Resist Fatigue 
Su ggestion 
Joe Sifferman (Order #46323384)

=== PAGE 71 ===
PSYC HIC SENS ITIVE 
ABILITIE S 
Astral Proje ction 
Range : Self 
Durati on: 5 minutes per level of experience. 
I.S.P. : 8 
Through intense conc entration/meditation (4D4 minutes of 
preparation) the psychic can free his mind, or inner self, from his 
physical body. This psychic inner self is the astral body, a whit¡
ish, semitransparent, ghostly image of the character's physical 
form. A long silver thread or cord connects the astral body with 
its physical self. If the cord is severed the character is likely to 
die of sudden shock as body and soul are tom asunder. There is 
only a 30% chance the astral self can locate its physical body 
without the silver umbilical cord (roll best 2 out of 3). 
The physical body lapses into a coma-like trance when the as¡
tral self has left it. In this state the body is completely helpless. It 
can not walk, move or think ; it is completely catatonic . 
The hazards are threefo ld. First, if the physical body is killed, 
the astral body is forever lost and will fade away within six 
hours. Secon d, if the astral body gets lost or captured while in 
the astral plane , the body will begin to wa ste away and die. 
(Note : One minute of our time is equal to one week in the astral 
plane). Third, the astral body is vulnerable to psychic attacks 
and attacks from ghosts, entities and creatures of the astral plane. 
There are two levels of astral projection, coexistence (physi¡
cal body and spirit form) in the material world and/or the astral 
plane (another dimension). Astral projection from the physical 
body into the material world creates a ghostly specter of the as¡
tral self which can be seen only by other psychic s, young chil¡
dren under 13 years old, animals and most supernatural 
creatures. While in astral form, the character automatically gains 
the ability to float, fly (mach one/670 mph maximum), see the 
invisible, pass through solid objects, impervious to physical 
harm (including cold, heat and energy ), and see and hear as 
usual. The astral body can not communica te with the physical 
world except through telepathy or empathy, nor speak to, smell 
or touch anything on the material plane . The astral self is little 
more than a mute, ghostly observer. Of course , this is a great 
way to locate invis ible supernatural entities, as well as spy on 
other humans on the material plane (although limited by short 
sprints. See duration). 
Traveling in astral form has its own very special dangers . 
While the character can see the invisi ble and other astral travel¡
ers, they can also see him. This makes him susceptible to their 
psychic and astral form attacks, for two astral travelers can lock 
into hand to hand combat as well. The most vulne rable target is 
the silver cord which is the astral traveler's lifeline to the phy si¡
cal world. Fortunately, the cord has an Astral SD.C. which is 
two times that of the person's physical hit points and S.D.C. 
combined. The thread-like silver cord is a difficult target to hit; 
attackers are -6 to strike. The astral body also has an S.D.C. two 
times greater than the hit points and S. D.C. of the physical body 
combined. This means if the character has 18 hit points and 28 
70 
S.D.C., both the astral body and its silver cord have 92 Astral 
S.D.C. each (1 8+28=46x2=92 each) . Remember, magic and psy¡
chic influence have full effect on the astral body. This includes 
exorcism, which will force the astral traveler to leave the imme¡
diate area (400ft radius) and not return for 24 hours. The astral 
traveler has the same number of attacks per melee, bonuses, 
hand to hand, skills, knowledge and psychic powers that he or 
she has in the material plane. 
Entering the astral plane is like entering the twilight zone. 
After a minute of concentration, the astral gateway appears as a 
bright patch of shimmering, white light. Once the astral traveler 
passes through it, he will find himself in an endless expanse of 
white light, and rolling, white clouds. There is no up or down, no 
bottom or top; no north or south, no land or air or sea, just end¡
less, slowly swirling white . Time too, is a different or altered 
state, for what would seem to be a week in the astral plane is 
barely one minute in the phy sical world. Time and space twisted 
and distorted, the astral traveler can travel from one end of our 
planet to the other, in the blink of an eye, by hopping through 
the astral plane . While this may sound wonderful, the astral 
plane has its dangers as well. First, the distortion of place and 
time makes it extremely difficult to find the material world and 
one 's dormant, physical body. Even trying to follow the silver 
cord can lead to nowhere. 
To return from the astral plane to the physical body, roll 
on the fo llowing table : Each roll will determine the astral trav¡
eler's state of mind and sense of direction. The percentile dice 
can be rolled up to three times per melee (15 seconds). The 
player must roll "definitely certain" to successfully return. The 
player may keep trying until he succeeds or time elapses. 
Location of the Physical Bo dy 
Roll Percentile Dice to Returnf rom the Astral Plane 
1-30 Hopelessly Lost (roll again). 
31-50 Uncertai n, confused (roll again) . 
51-76 Fairly certain of location; on the right track (roll again) . 
77-00 Definitely certain of location. (Wh ew ! Made it Back). 
ò Astral travel with a partner is a much safer way to travel, be¡
cause if one can find his body, he can lead the other one out 
with him. 
Note : Traveling on the material plane in astral form is infi¡
nitely easier than the astral plane. To find the physical body, the 
character need only return to where he left it. If it has been 
moved or hidden , the astral self can sense its location with a 
60% efficiency (roll once per melee). 
The other danger lies in being attacked by other beings in 
the astral plane. Entities and elemental creatures of magic live in 
the astral plane or travel through it. These beings are usually 
hostile, evil forces. While the astral body can not touch or com¡
munica te with the material world, the astral body is quite solid to 
other inhabitants of the astral plane. The astral body is also vul¡
nerable to magic and psychic powers, as well as physical assault 
by astral entitie s. 
The energy which composes the astral plane is responsive to 
thoughts and desires. The strongest astral beings can mentally or 
magically control what a small area might look like. This means 
that the astral plane is made up of hundreds or perhaps thou¡
sands or even millions of tiny astral "kingdoms" adrift within the 
vast whitene ss. Exactly what these kingdoms look like is up to 
the entity that creates it. Some may look like a modem city, 
Joe Sifferman (Order #46323384)

=== PAGE 72 ===
other castles or forests, while still others, a frightening land¡
scape. Perhaps this is where legends of vis itations to heaven and 
hell origina te? It is always wise to avoid an astral kingdom, be¡
cause only the most powerful entiti es and astral beings can cre¡
ate and maintain them. In Professor Vict or Lazlo 's book, 
"Worlds Within Wor lds," he provides us with this firsthand ac¡
count of astral travel : 
"A lthough I myself have only minuscule psychic abilities, 
what might be considered a latent psychic (very latent), I had 
never been able to achieve astral projection . However, lord, 
high priest Vish-taal assured me that he could help me achieve 
the reputed state and lead me into the astral plane. So I bravely 
began my excursion into the ethereal realm that coexists with 
our own . Af ter nine days of fa sting, consuming only herb broth 
prepared by Vish-taal once per day, I was ready at last. We 
meditated together fo r three hours then, bef ore I realized it, I 
was looking down at my own body. The sensation must be akin 
to floating in the weight lessness of space . The room seemed 
somewhat out of scale and distorted, like looking through a fi sh¡
eye lens. Suddenly I realized Vish-taal was floating next to me. 
He assured me that all was well and that af ter a fe w more out of 
body experiences I could see the material world as clear as nor¡
mal. But today our goal was the astral plan e. He took hold of my 
shoulder and beckoned me to come. With that, we both rose up¡
ward through the ceilings of the next three floors, the roof and 
skyward. I must conf ess that my 23 years as an investigator of 
the paranormal had not prepared me fo r this experience. All my 
prof essional cool had fled me the moment I left my body. I was 
so enthralled with the event s and images that without the guid¡
ance of Vish-taal I would have bobbed about the room like a 
dumf ounded child seeing Disneyland fo r the first time. Every¡
thing seemed to sweep by me, stealing my fu ll attention fo r that 
moment, giving away to the next sensation and the next. As I 
sped skyward at a speed I can not begin to guess, the sparkling 
body of my astral guide caught my atten tion. For the fi rst time, I 
noticed that our astral bodies were aglow with a bright, translu¡
cent, blue-white light with countless tiny flashes of white, yellow, 
and blue light, like a thousand microscopic strobe lights set fo r a 
slow pulse. A thread of translucent silver unreeled itself as we 
rocketed ahe ad. Vish-taalyanked my attention with the words the 
gatewa y' . Bef ore us was a glittering wall of light which we 
plunged through at great speed, without pause. Suddenly we 
were plunged into a world of swirling white, broken only by 
wisps of white clouds. There was no longer any sense of up or 
down. Direction had no meaning . Without my astral guide to 
calm me I would have become lost in the vastness of the white 
inf inity. Vish-taal assured me that with training one could sense 
the material world and use it like an invisible compass. I must 
admit that af ter what seemed to be about a half hour, I was able 
to discern shapes and patterns in the endless white clouds and 
mists. A strange calm seemed to take hold of me and made the 
whiteness seem fa r less alien . Then, af ter a long while, appear¡
ing through a fo g-like mist stood a fo rest. Shades of green and 
brown and grey leaped out of the whiteness . A blue sky broken 
by cumulus clouds radiated around the green. Without realizing 
it, I had automatically gravitated toward the oasis of color. Sud¡
denly, a sensation of evil shot through me like a hundred burn¡
ing needles. Never in my experience as a minor psychic sensitive 
had I ever fe lt such hatred, such loathing. To my left a billow of 
grey and black storm clouds began to roll out fr om the green 
71 
trees. The blue sky darkened and the clouds shot toward me with 
an anger I can not describe. Vish-taal' s voice echoed in my 
ears : Go now we must, Victor. We should not try battle with this 
one. Now Victor, away from the dark. Flee with me and look not 
back. ' We sped through the white and I did not look back. Obvi¡
ously, I survived to tell this tale. When we returned to our physi¡
cal bodies, I was still shaking. Vish-taal smiled knowingly and 
said, Victor, you see much adventure this day. I will send fo od 
while you much relax. ' With a wink, the old yogi left me with my 
own thoughts. 
"T he experience seemed to last several hours. I would hazard 
to guess eight or nine . Yet the wall clock confirmed with my 
wristwatch that less than six minutes had actua lly elapsed. Did I 
experience astral travel? Or was it sensory depriva tion ? The 
wily old priest could have easily drugged my broth or even hyp¡
notized me. I had seen him expertly use hypnosis on others on 
countless occasions. But the old man and I had been fr iends fo r 
years and I hon estly don 't think my mentor would deceive me. So 
this then was the astral plane. I wish I could relate the details 
with greater clarity, but as I said, my objectivity and skills as an 
investigative reporter deserted me. One thing that did strike me 
was how much my astral plane experience seemed to mimic the 
transmissions of Lt. Taylor from Flight 19, which disappeared in 
19 45 over the Bermuda Triangle. In that celebrated and much 
disputed case, fi ve Air Force Avenger Torpedo Bombers disap¡
peared during a routine flight near Ft. Lauderdale, Florida. The 
leader's (Lt. Taylor) radio transmissions were bizarre. He re¡
ported that both compasses were out, and on a fa irly clear win¡
ter af ternoon, could not find Ft. Lauderdale. Other 
transmissions speak of vast whiteness and swirling clouds. Of 
not being able to fi nd the sun or ascertain any sense of direction. 
Not even up or down. The transmissions fa ded in and out until 
they stopped. The fi nal transmission: "W e'l l fly west until we hit 
the beach or run out of gas. " Flight 19 disappeared without a 
trace. The most logical explanation is that the five aircraft per¡
ished in a sudden squall; not that any storms were known to 
have arisen that af ternoon. Is it possible that some mysterious 
fo rce opened a portal into the astral plane? A portal that the five 
bombers, and a sixth search aircraft and its crew of thirteen, in¡
adverten tly flew into ? It is a possibility I must investigate fu r¡
ther. " 
Excerptedfrom Victor Lazlo's WORLDS WITHIN WORLDS, 19 77. 
Clairvoyance 
Range : Self (although the image could pertain to people or 
places thousands of miles away. 
Du rati on: 6D6 melees 
I.S.P.: 4 
Ba se Skill : 58%+2% per level of experience. 
This allows the psychic to see or feel glimpses of the possible 
future. This is achieved through meditation or intense concentra¡
tion in which the clairvoyant thinks about a particular person, 
event or place. Add +5% to the base skill if the person involved 
is a friend or loved one. Clairvoyance is unpredictable and can 
not be turned on and off like a light bulb. Sometimes it works (if 
the roll is under the base skill) and sometimes it does not (when 
the roll is above the base skill). A failed roll means the psychic 
received no insight to the future. 
Joe Sifferman (Order #46323384)

=== PAGE 73 ===
A clairvoyant trance can be attempted as often as twice every 
day. The message can be a sudden feeling that somebody is in 
need ("something 's wrong. It 's Janet ! I'v e got to see her!") or, 
more often, a sudden flash of insig ht, a sudden image that races 
through the mind. The image is like a brief snippet of film from 
a movie or a dream. Often all the details are not clear, but the 
potential danger is. For example, "The psychic character is in a 
trance or meditation, thinking about his/her friend Janet. Sud¡
denly, the mind is flooded with an image of Janet rushing down 
a crowded street. It 's dusky, like morning, twil ight or evening. 
She seems very upset. The traffic light changes to amber. Janet 
races into the street, ignoring the light. It turns red. There 's a car, 
squeal of tir es, Janet screams. The image ends. Is Janet hurt? 
Killed? Unkn own, but the danger is clear. There are also other 
hints of information: the time of day, Janet seeming upset, rush¡
ing, etc. The glimpse into the future could be twenty minutes, 
eight hours, 24 hours, or a week. The psychic has no way of 
knowing. Of course , he has the advantage of recognizing the po¡
tential danger as it begins to unfold and may be able to avoid it, 
stop it or change the outcome . The image may last a few minutes 
or be a sudden flash lasting but a few seconds. The flash could 
be a peculiar noise, a face, or a specific image, like a particular 
door or object. 
It is important to note that sometimes a clairvoyant image will 
occur unintention ally, without the psychic trying to do so. These 
most often manifest themselves as dreams or nightmares during 
sleep. The clairvoyant dream is exactly like the image from a 
meditative trance described previously . The precognitive flash of 
the future may also occur unbeckoned while awake , but this is 
extremely rare. These brief glimpses of the possible future hap¡
pen because the clairvoyant is acutely attuned to his world. Any¡
thing that might hurt or change that world (including people and 
places) will often be foretold in a flash of insight. 
Game Mast ers: Be careful of revealing too much. Use the 
examples provided as a guide. Remember, these are brief 
glimpses of the possible future, not a motion picture. The psy¡
chic can NOT engage in any actions, combat or otherwise, dur¡
ing a moment of clairvoyance or the image will instantly stop. It 
usually requires 2D4 melees of concentration or meditation be¡
fore the image occurs. Remember, a failed base skill roll means 
absolutely nothing happens, but still bums up the 4 I.S.P. and the 
time. 
Death Trance 
Range : Self 
Duration : As long as the psychic senses he must feign death, up 
to a maximum of four days. 
I.S.P.: 2 
A state of mind over matter that slows the metabolism to such 
a degree that it creates a temporary state of suspended anima¡
tion, simulating death. Without hospital facilitie s, even a medi¡
cal doctor is likely to believe the character is dead (1 -89% 
likelihoo d). The effects of drugs, toxins and chemicals are 
slowed to a crawl, doing damage or effect, but will take full ef¡
fect the instant the death trance is stopped (unless treatment is 
administered first). Wh ile in the death-like state, the psychic 
cannot be roused or respond to any type of stimulation, includ¡
ing psychic probes. This means he is incapable of attacking or 
defending himself in any way until the trance is broken. 
72 
Divi nation 
Range : Self 
Dura tion : 2D4 minutes 
I.S.P.: 3 
Ba se Ski ll: 42%+2% per each additional level of experience. 
Divina tion is a precognitive ability to sense the future. 
Throughout the history of the world there have been fortunetell¡
ers who claim to foretell the future by reading tarot cards, sticks, 
palms, tea leaves and other thing s. This precognitive power is 
much less accurate and detailed than clairvoyance. With divina¡
tion there is no image, no sound, no tangible memory or flash, 
only an impression. 
To perform a divination, the diviner must meditate for at least 
15 or 20 minutes. The tools or ite m(s) read by the fortuneteller 
are laid out/spilled before the psychic , their random patterns pro¡
viding hint s to the future. No specific questions or details can be 
revealed, such as, "Yes, if you go to the house this evening you 
will be attacked by a madman and murdered with a knife." In¡
stead, what might be revealed is something like, "I see the spec¡
ter of death. It waits hungrily. I see violence and yes, madness." 
or "Death awaits you at the house." Neither says that the charac¡
ter will be killed, but does confirm that somebody or something 
may be out to kill him. This is the way divina tion should work, 
small impressions of the possible future. The game master 
should never predetermine the outcome of a game or an event 
within a game. Like real life, there are too many x-factors which 
can change what may seem inevita ble. Conse quently, keep the 
divina tion answers a bit general to give yourself maximum flexi¡
bili ty of play. NEVER make a situation completely hopeless! 
The diviner can try to divina te his own future, but with a -
10 % skill penalty, or the future of ONE person at a time. The 
person can ask up to 13 questions which the diviner will try to 
answer. The divining character must roll percentile dice for each 
question . A failed roll means he senses nothing and cannot an¡
swer the question . Professional fortunetellers will make up some 
intrig uing line of malarkey like, "The wheels of the future are al¡
ways turning. Too many things could influence your future in 
this regard (in answer to the questio n). Proceed with caution." or 
"So mething blocks my visi on . I can tell you nothing." 
There are all types of methods and items of divina tion. The 
psychic 's personal orientation/focus must be limited to one or 
two types. Sel ect one (or two maximum) focuses/objects needed 
for divination . Note : The character cannot see into the future 
without using the item(s). 
DIVINATION FORMS TABLE 
ARITHMA NCY: The use of numbers, either in patterns 
which reoccur around the person or selected randomly, to tell 
their past or predict their future. See also Numerology. 
ASTRAGALOMA NCY: Div ination by the use of dice or 
marked pieces of bone. This technique includes modem dice, the 
Viking system of "casting the runes" and the casting of human 
and animal knucklebones used by African witch doctors. 
BELO MANC Y: Foretelling the future by throwing arrows to 
the ground and observing the pattern they form. This particular 
technique would be well suited to primitive or modem, bow-us¡
ing cultures. 
CARTOMA NCY: This form of divination is done literally by 
the "tum of a card." It uses special decks of cards, known as 
Joe Sifferman (Order #46323384)

=== PAGE 74 ===
Tarot, but can also be done with a regular deck of playing cards. 
Each card is ascribed a specific meaning and are laid in a pat¡
tern. Meditation on the cards and the pattern they form give the 
divina tion . Cartomancy has always been one of the most popular 
kinds of fortunetelling and has existed from the time of the Phar¡
aohs of Egypt. 
CEP HALOMA NCY: This divina tory skill uses the bumps 
and depressions which can be found on a person's skull to pre¡
dict their future. It is vaguely related to palmistry in that the per¡
son's entire future is supposed to be written on their body. 
CHIROMA NCY: Also known as palmistry, this art teaches 
the user to read the future in the lines found in the palms of the 
questioner 's hands. Each line is supposed to govern one particu¡
lar area of life, including Life, Love and Fortune. 
CRYSTALOMA NCY: Another very common form of divi¡
nation, this technique uses a crystal ball as an aid for seeing into 
the future. There are many arguments among experts as to 
whether the answe rs/visions actually appear within the crystal or 
just within the mind of the seer, who uses the crystal only as a 
focus. 
EMPROMA NCY: This is divina tion by the studying of ob¡
jects placed in a sacrificial fire, es pecially as to any shapes or 
forms seen in the smoke or the fire itself. 
GEOMA NCY: Divina tion by tossing pebbles on the ground 
and analyzing the pattern they form. The pebbles can either be 
special ceremonial stones, or they can simply be a handful of 
stones picked up on a beach. 
HYDROMA NCY: This skill requires the use of a small pool 
of water in which the seer analyzes the ripples and other di stur¡
bances of the pool itself. 
ICTHYOMA NCY: Very popular in cultures which depend 
upon fish for existence, this is divina tion by the examination of 
the entrails of a fish. 
KLEIDO MANCY: By suspending a pendulum over an al¡
phabet and asking questions, the pendulum is supposed to spell 
out the answers . A cousin to this skill today is the modem Oui ja 
board. 
LECANOMA NCY: One of the most beautiful and most ex¡
pensive of the divina tory arts, gems are dropped into still pools 
of water and the ripples they create are analyzed for hints about 
the future. 
MOLYBDOMA NCY: This is divina tion by observing the 
pattern formed by molten lead after it has been dropped onto a 
smooth surface. 
NUMEROL OGY : A very popular form of divination for the 
last hundred years or so, this art analyzes numbers connected to 
a person's name and date of birth, using a very stringent system 
for reducing alphabetical names to numbers. 
PESSOMANC Y: This is divina tion by observing the size, 
shape, texture, etc., of a pebble drawn randomly from a pile. 
PHYLLORHODOMA NCY: Taking literally the old saw 
that each flower carries a message, this technique analyzes the 
pattern formed by the petals and leaves of a rose to divine the fu¡
ture. 
PYROMA NCY: According to the practitioners of this tech¡
nique , by analyzing a fire, paying special attention to the flames 
and any smoke or sparks, the future can be told. 
73 
TASSEOG RAPHY : This is the reading of tea leaves; a spe¡
cialty of old women in tea houses and restaurants around the 
world. 
XYLOMA NCY: This technique analyzes the pattern of 
spikes thrown on the ground. So mewhat related to Belomancy, 
the best known example of this system is the Chinese "I Chin g," 
or Book of Change s, system. 
Empa thy 
Range : 10 0 foot area (30.5 m) 
Du rati on: Two minutes (8 melees) per level of experience. 
I.S.P. : 4 
Saving Throw : Standard; a save vs empathy means the psychic 
can not get a clear sense of the emotions of that particular 
person. To save vs empathy the person must roll to save once 
each melee. Mind block will prevent any empathic emana¡
tions from the blocked person. 
Empathy is a psi-ability that makes the psychic aware of, or 
feel, the emotions of other people, animals and supernatural 
creatures. The strongest emotions are easiest to sense: hate, an¡
ger, terror, love. Feeling for emotions can often be used to estab¡
lish that somebody or something is nearby, but can not be used 
to pinpoint an invisi ble or hiding person/creature. Empathy can 
be especially helpful in recognizing and communicating with 
ghosts and other supernatural creatures. 
Questioning a person/being while using empathy can be very 
handy in establishing how they are reacting to you. In a limited 
sense, empathy can be used like a lie detector to see if the emo¡
tions match the verbal response. For Example: "Did you know 
the deceased?" The verbal answer is no, but there is a sudden 
flare of nervousness and fear (or hate). This doesn't mean the 
guy is the killer, but it might mean he is lying about knowing the 
dead man. Further questions might pull out a strong emotion 
such as anger or hate (or happiness), which may confirm the 
psychic 's suspicions that this man might be involved in the mur¡
der. However, remember that this is, at best, circumstantial evi¡
dence and definitely inadmissible in court. Physical proof must 
be found, but the empathic readings may put characters on the 
right track. Also, remember that the empathic psychic is feeling 
the person's real emotions, not interpreting their significa nce. A 
very nervous person may always radiate fear or anxiety, while a 
cold-blooded, pathological killer may feel nothing at all and stay 
calm and cool as he lies through his teeth. The feeling of hate 
may mean that the person did know the murder victim, or knew 
of him, and hated him for any number of reasons. That does not 
mean he killed him. As you can see, interpreting emotions can 
be a tricky thing. 
Haunting ghosts and entities rarely mask their emotions. 
Thus, the psychic can easily tell if one or more is nearby (within 
10 0 feet/30.5 m) and what it is feeling. "I sense great sorrow." or 
"Do as it says ! It is angry, almost crazed. I think it will carry out 
its threat if you try to stop it." 
Empa thic Transmission 
Range : 60 feet (1 8.2 m) 
Durati on: 2D6 minutes (2 to 12 minutes) 
I.S.P. : 6 
Attacks Per Melee : Equal to the individual 's psychic abilities; 
usually 2 or 3 psi-attacks per melee. 
Joe Sifferman (Order #46323384)

=== PAGE 75 ===
Saving Throw: Standard 
This incredible ability enables the psychic to instill a power¡
ful emotion into another liv ing creature; person, animal or super¡
natural being. Each psychic attack/transmission can only affect 
one creature at a time. Sev eral supernatural creatures have this 
ability or some aspect of it. 
Despair or Sorrow : Invokes great emotional upheaval, deep 
sorrow and a sense of loss. There is a 50% chance of the victim 
surrendering or leaving without a battle; furthermore, victims are 
-2 to parry and dodge. 
Confus ion : Diso rients the person so badly that he has no 
sense of direction, time, or of what is exactly going on. Victims 
are -3 to strike, parry and dodge, and lose initiative in any com¡
bat. 
Fear: Invokes unr easoning terror in all those affected. Victims 
are -3 to strike, parry and dodge, plus there is a 66% chance that 
those affected will tum and run. 
Hate or Anger : Will prompt those affected to act rashly, 
charge, attack, argue violent ly, etc. Victims are likely (60% 
chance) to attack, kill, harm, or betray those they dislike; + 1 
(yes, that's plus) to strike, -1 to parry and dodge. 
Love or Peacefulness : Will induce a deep feeling of serenity, 
dispelling anger, hatred, sorrow, and so on. Hostile opponents 
are likely (60% chance) to reconsider their actions, deciding not 
to attack, show mercy, leave without being overtly cruel or de¡
structive, halt a rampage, and so on. It does NOT make its vic¡
tims docile sheep, but curbs hostility . 
Trust: Will make its victims believe everything the psionic 
tells them, but only while under the empathic influence . Life 
threatening suggestions that go against deep-seated fears or ide¡
als provide an additional savings throw against the sugge sted ac¡
tion; with a bonus of +3 to save. 
Med itation 
Range : Self 
Dura tion : Var ies with the person's needs. 
I.S.P.: None 
Meditation is the only ability that can be done at any time and 
costs no I.S. P. to perform. Meditation is not so much a psychic 
power, as it is a mental discipline. The character meditates by 
dwelling upon a single notion, mental object, or mantra (a repeti¡
tiou s chant or humming ), to achieve a deep relaxation, focus, or 
to gain insight and harmony into one 's inner self, nature and the 
universe . Meditation is often required to use psychic and magic 
powers. 
Mediumship /Clairsentience (S eance) 
Range : Self 
Dura tion: 2D4 minutes (plus 3D4 minutes of preparation) 
I.S.P. : 4 
Base Skill : 30%+2% for every P.P.E point that can be drawn on. 
Some individuals are especially sensitive to psychic impres¡
sions and can open themselves to the supernatural forces. The 
clairsentience power operates on two le vels. First: The psychic 
sensitive acts as a beacon, calling out to haunting ghosts or other 
entities. This makes the psychic 's presence known, as well as in¡
vites the entity (s) to come forth and communica te. 
74 
Second, the psychic acts as a medium through which the entity 
can speak (temporary possessi on) or as the mediator (the person 
who asks the question s). As the mediator of a seance group, 
someone other than the psychic beacon is temporarily possessed, 
but only the mediator can ask question s. The spirit or entity will 
temporarily enter the medium or psychically susceptible member 
of a seance group to communicate . The voice is often the voice 
of the spirit force, not the person, and might be in a foreign lan¡
guage. The entity may not speak at all, but write or draw its mes¡
sage. Communications are usually brief, seldom lasting more 
than five minutes and ending abruptly. The entity is not bound to 
answer questions truthfully, although good alignments have no 
reason to lie (evil entities lie freely). The person selected as the 
"mouthpiece" will remember nothing that occurred while pos¡
sessed. If the person has latent psychic powers or many P.P.E. 
points, the possessi ng force will be able to draw on that energy 
reserve to create other phenomena such as telekine sis, empathic 
transfer, etc. The spirit's words and actions can not be control¡
led, making physical manifestations all the more frightening. 
This accounts for gusts of wind, rapping, table movement, etc. 
Fortunately, the possessi on is short-lived, or contact can be bro¡
ken by breaking the chain in the seance. 
The seance chain is composed of a group of people who sit, 
holding each other's hands to create a circle. The group can be a 
mere two people or as many as a dozen. It is pointless for the 
psychic medium to open himself up to a seance without at least 
one other, because he can not remember what happens while un¡
der the control of the entity . Another reason for having several 
people is that each person can feed the medium with their own 
potential psychic energy (P.P.E.). Each person in the seance 
chain can temporarily contribute up to half of his/her P.P.E. to 
the cause. The only requirement is to truly desire communication 
with a supernatural force. Each supporter of the communication 
link adds P.P.E. fuel. Each P.P.E. point increases the bases skill 
by +2%. The psychic medium can draw on all of his P.P.E. 
points, which is usually 8 or 10. Every P.P.E. point from a per¡
son opposed to the communica tion reduces the success ratio by -
2%. A nega-psychic who is a member of a seance chain will 
reduce the success by -4% per each of his P.P.E. points. How¡
ever, the nega-psychic can observe a seance without any ill ef¡
fects. The use of the P.P.E. energies is momentary and returns to 
full level within minutes, but may leave some participants with a 
slight feeling of dizziness or fatigue for those few minutes. The 
seance can be broken at any time by letting go of each other's 
hands. Game Mast er's Note : The behavior of the ghost or en¡
tity that communica tes through the medium will depend on the 
type of entity , its alignment and its plans. Many haunting ghosts 
want help if they can get it, while poltergeists are pure mischief. 
The more powerful, evil entities may mislead or mock the char¡
acters, or even lash out during a seance, using the participants' 
own P.P.E. against them. However, a seance assault is usually 
more frightening than deadly. The spirit force can communicate 
in voice, writing, symbols/drawings, or sometimes with telepa¡
thy or empathic transfer as well. A brief gust of wind often 
whips up out of nowhere, small objects are knocked over or rat¡
tle about, the table may move or levitate as much as two feet 
above the floor and another psychic may sense the entity 's emo¡
tions. The most sensational and violent seances may produce 
hurling objects which can inflict minor physical damage to the 
seance participants, ectoplasmic apparitions , empathic transmis-
Joe Sifferman (Order #46323384)

=== PAGE 76 ===
sions (usually fear, confusion or despair) and even magic 
spells/assaults. Regardless of the strength and ferocity of the 
creature 's response/onslaught, the seance can always be inst antly 
stopped by just one person breaking the chain of holding hands . 
The moment somebody lets go, the mini-circle of P.P.E. power 
is broken and the entity is dispelled from the host medium's 
body. At that same instant, all physical and mental manifesta¡
tions cease. 
In the case of non-psychic seance attempts (ordinary people 
without the aid of a professi onal psychic or medium), the base 
skill is equal to the number of P.P.E. points linked by the hand 
holding. The person with the most P.P.E. or one with latent psy¡
chic abilities is the likely one to be selected by the entity to com¡
munica te through. 
Mind Block 
Range : Self 
Durati on: 10 minutes per level of experience. 
I.S.P.: 4 (per each duration period) 
This is the ability to completely close or block oneself from 
all psychic /mental emanations. When intenti onally closed to su¡
pernatural or psychic forces, the character can not sense any¡
thing, can not use psychic abilit ies, nor be influenced by others. 
A mind block will prevent penetration of telepathy , empathy, 
hypnotic suggestion, and empathic transfer. It can be an invalu¡
able protective mask when dealing with malevolen t psychic 
forces. Adds a bonus of + I to save vs all psychic and mental at¡
tacks. 
Obje ct Read (Psychometry) 
Range : Touch 
Du rati on: Var ies; usually about 2D6 minutes. 
I.S.P. : 6 
Saving Throw: None 
Ba se Skill : Impressions: 56%+2% per level of experience. Im¡
ages: 48%+2% per level . Present: 38% +2% per level of ex¡
perience. 
This unc anny ability enables the psychic sensitive to receive 
impressions and images from an object regarding its use, history 
and last owner. This is done by holding the object and concen¡
trating on a specific line of thought or opening up to general im¡
pressions (the latter is always more vague and random). Just as a 
psychic must open himself to sense evil or magic, he must open 
himself to the object. If successful, he will receive impressi ons 
and/or images revealing bits of information. 
Impressions include: General align ment of its last owner 
(good, selfish, evil), general emotional state of mind (anger, 
happy, sad, hate-filled, confused, etc.), the objec t's general pur¡
pose (what it is used for), whether or not the last owner is living 
or dead, and whether the item has been used with/by magic or 
supernatural forces. Object read will also conclusively indica te 
whether the item is currently enchanted or contains a supernatu¡
ral force/entity (as well as its align ment and emotions). If the 
item is possessed, an object read makes the reader totally vulner¡
able to psychic attack (no bonuses to save) . 
Images : The psychic can also see images of isolated events 
which have happened in the past. This will provide brief snip¡
pets of images and events that will offer glances of the previous 
7S 
owner and others close to him. Traumatic and emotion filled 
events /images are the easiest to see. Impressions will accompany 
the images, adding to the story as it unf olds. Inf ormation in¡
cludes: approximate age, height, weight, build, race, sex, some¡
times occupation, hair color and length; special facial or body 
features, such as a scar or tattoo or beard (very often the exact 
facial features are out of focus, blurred or obscured); the object's 
use/purpose; and some special event, usually very traumatic, im¡
portant or happy. Often the event image will be fragmented as if 
it was a piece of movie film edited by a crazy man. The event 
will always be one in which the object was involved in some 
way. 
The present can also be glimpsed, but costs an additional 4 
LS. P., with no guarantee of succe ss. Sometimes the psychic can 
focus in to see and feel the last owner as he or she is at that very 
moment. This will provide an idea of what is his current state of 
mind/emotion, appearance/dress, general location (that is to say, 
a bedroom, office, street, outdoors, etc. No address or sense of 
close or far is provided), general features (shaved his beard, 
dyed hair, etc.) and so on. The psychic may be able to identify a 
place or person by feature, if he has seen it before or runs into 
it/him in the near future. 
The success or failure of an object read: roll percentile dice 
once for impressi ons and once for images. The roll must fall un¡
der the character's base skill ability to succeed. A roll higher 
than the base skill means a failure and the psychic feels and/or 
sees nothing. Impressions and images are two different things, so 
roll fo r each. The psychic may get no impressions, but see im¡
ages or vice versa. The present can not be seen unless the psy¡
chic was successful on at least one of the previous read 
impressi ons or images rolls. Once an object has been read it can 
not be read again by the same psychic, even if he did not see or 
feel a thing. Of course , the psychic can attempt to object read 
other items, but each attempt will cost 6 LS. P. 
Presence Sense 
Range : 12 0 foot/36 m area 
Du ration: 2 minutes (8 melees) per level of experience. 
I.S.P.: 4 
Saving Throw : None 
Presence sense is a sixth sense which will alert the character to 
the presence of supernatural and magic creatures in the area. The 
ability can not pinpoint the location of the presence, but will 
give the psychic the impression of whether it is near (within 50 
feet/15.2 m) or far (beyond 90 feet/27.4 m). It will also give the 
character a vague idea of how many presences there are; one (1 
or 2), a few (3 to 6), several (7 to 14 ), or many (15 or more). The 
psychic can also sense human presences, but with much less ac¡
curacy . It is more of a feeling of "We are not alone ." The per¡
son's distance is undeterminable and the number of people is 
limited to a sense of one or two or many (and that is only right 
50% of the time). 
See Aura 
Range : 60 feet (1 8.3 m) and must be visi ble. 
Dura tion: 2 melees (30 seconds) 
I.S.P.: 6 
Saving Throw : None, but a mind block will hide the presence 
Joe Sifferman (Order #46323384)

=== PAGE 77 ===
of psychic abilities, the level of P.P.E., and possessi on by a 
supernatural force. 
All thing s, organic and inorganic , have an aura. The aura has 
many distinctions and ca n be used to see or sense things invis¡
ible to the eye. Seeing an aura will indicate the jollowing: 
ò Estimate the general level of experience. Low (1-3), medium 
(4-7), high (8th and up). 
ò The presence of magic (no indica tion of what or power level). 
ò The presence of psychic abilitie s. 
ò High or low base P.P.E. 
ò The presence of a possessi ng entity . 
ò The presence of an unusual human aberration which indica tes 
a serious illness, non-human, or mutant, but does not specify 
which. 
Note : Can not tell one 's alignment from "see aura." 
See The Invisible 
Range : 12 0 foot/36 m distances. 
Durati on: 1 minute per each level of experience. 
IoSoP.: 4 
Saving Throw: None 
The character can see forces, objects and creatures which can 
tum invisi ble or are naturally invisible. Even if the creatures 
have no form per se, the psychic will be able to discern the va¡
porous image or energy sphere which is the being. This includes 
ghosts, entities and the astral body. 
Sense Evil 
Range : 14 0 foot/42.7 m area. 
Dura tion : 2 minutes (8 melees) per level of experience. 
I.S.P.: 2 
Saving Throw: None 
This psi-power is a much more refined ability to feel the pres¡
ence of evil. All supernatural creatures radiate their alignment, 
good or evil. A psychic sensitive will automatically feel super¡
natural evil without spending a single I.S. P. However, to get a 
clearer picture of the evil force(s) the character must open him¡
self and use the sense evil ability . 
The sense evil psi-power will indica te the general number of 
supernatural evil: one, a few (2-6), several (7-14), or many (15 
or more). It can also register the intensity of the evil and pinpoint 
the general location of the source(s) to a particular room(s), pos¡
sessed object or person, or distance; i.e. very near (within 15 
feet/4.5 m), near (within 50 feet/15. 2 m), or far (60 to 14 0 
feet/1 8.2 to 42.7 m). The character can track the source of super¡
natural evil, like a bloodhound, by sensing how close it is to him. 
76 
Evil emanations from human beings are much less distinct 
and can not be felt unless the source-person has an immediate 
evil intention and has psychic powers or is psychotic. The for¡
mer can mask his evil intentions with a mind block. 
Sense Magic 
Range : 12 0 foot/36 m area 
Durat ion: 2 minutes per level of experience. 
IoSoP. : 3 
Saving Throw: None 
The ability to sense magic is much like the sense evil psi¡
power. The psychic can feel magic energy, tell whether it is near 
(within 20 feet/6.1 m) or far (up to 12 0 feet/36 m away) and fol¡
low the emanations to pinpoint their source as a particular place, 
room, person or ob ject. Note : Invisible, magica l supernatural 
creatures or ob jects can only be traced to a general area, like a 
specific room or comer. The psychic will also be able to sense 
whether or not an object has magic powers, if a person or item is 
enchanted/under a magic spell (this does not include psychic 
powers), when magic is being used within the area (12 0 feet) 
and when a person is casting a spell (users of magic do not radi¡
ate magic energies until they call upon them). 
Sixth Sense 
Range : 90 feet/27.4 m 
Du rati on: Until the danger passes or happens. 
I.S.P. : 2 
Saving Throw: None 
The sixth sense is a power that gives the psychic a precogni¡
tive flash of imminent danger to himself or somebody near him 
(within 90 feet/27.4 m). The character will not know what the 
danger is or where it will come from, nor who it will be directed 
at when in a group. All he will know is that something life 
threatening will happen within the next 60 seconds (4 melees)! 
The sixth sense is triggered automatically, without the consent 
of the psychic, whenever his life is in great peril or the life of 
somebody he greatly cares about (friend, loved one, etc.). The 
sixth sense is only triggered by an unexpected, lif e threatening 
event which is already set into motion and will happen any sec¡
ond. The power can not be called upon at will to sense for traps 
or ambush. Instead, it works like an automatic reflex. If the char¡
acter has used all his I.S .P. the sixth sense is temporarily ren¡
dered inoperative. 
Bo nuses : 
The sudden flash of insight provides the following bonuses. 
All bonuses apply only to the initia l melee when the attack oc¡
curs. 
+6 on initiative roll 
+2 to parry 
+3 to dodge 
The character can not be surprised by a sneak attack from be¡
hind. 
Sp eed Reading 
Range : Self 
Dura tion : 3 minutes per level of experience. 
IoSoPo : 2 
Joe Sifferman (Order #46323384)

